I guess we can get started alright so
today we're going to talk about back
prop and I'm sure for some of you a lot
of this is gonna look familiar
I'm going to start with some sort of
ring pressure is about busy concepts and
in talked about sort of a more general
formulation of back prop a little later
and then tomorrow alfredo will go
through like how you use Otto grad and
things like this in PI torch
okay so basic concepts we have
parameterize models so parameterize
models are nothing more than functions
that depends on that depend on two
parameters an input and a trainable
parameter and there is no conceptual
difference between the parameter and the
input they're just they're both
parameters of the of the deterministic
function the the thing is though the
parameter is shared across training
samples whereas the samples of course
are different for every training samples
so in things like in most deep learning
for Mark's the parameter is actually
implicit to the to the parameterize
function when you call the function you
don't actually pass the parameter value
it's sort of stored inside if you if at
least in the object-oriented versions of
models but just need to remember that
you know you have primary trans model is
just a prioritized function it takes an
input and it has a parameter vector it
produces an output in simple supervised
running this output goes into a cost
function that compares the output of the
model with the output you want here is
called C the prediction the output of
the module is called Y bar and the C
function compared Y in Y bar where why
is he at what you want Y bar is he I put
the output you get so I'm giving here
two very simple examples parameterized
functions which I'm sure you're familiar
with the first one is a linear model so
a linear model just computes a weighted
sum of the components of its input
vector multiply
by weights and if you do linear
regression with queloz
the the C function is just the squared
distance you create a distance between
the Y vector and the Y bar vector when y
bar can be vectors or scalars or tensors
or whatever doesn't matter things with
numbers in them basically or things that
you can compute distances between that's
actually all you need technically but
who needs a slightly more complicated
prioritized function here down on the
bottom which actually computes nearest
neighbor so here there is the input X
and then W is a matrix each row of the
matrix is indexed by the index K and to
compute the output we actually I put the
number K that corresponds to the row of
W that is closest to X okay so we
compute the distance between X and a
particular row of W which is wk and then
we value overall case and we figure out
which of those difference is smallest
okay
and we output that K so augment that's
what the argument function does right it
returns the the value of the argument
that minimizes the function right so
it's a function of K and that returns
the K that minimizes that function the
point I'm making with this which is a
complicated way of explaining nearest
neighbor is that the the type of
competition that takes place in your
parametrize model could be very
complicated it doesn't have to be just
like a neuron that something that you
compute with weighted sums and and
anomaly era T's it can be something
complicated and involves a minimization
of something else
I mean what could be the minima with
some function okay and we'll come back
to this in a few weeks
yes
you can denote it in a different way I
could have written W the W matrix
multiplied by let's say the Z vector and
the Z vector would be constrained to be
a a one hut and in which case we would
select a column of W and you could do a
mean over this is a vector okay then it
would be a different notation but kind
of a different effect a similar effect
but then you know I would have to read
to write to another equation like you
know Z is one hot and explain what that
means let me forget about the notation
you know just remember the fact that
there could be something complicated
going on in this parameterize function
it's not necessarily just you know a
very simple very simple thing so what
I've done with this diagram here is that
I've introduced a sort of way of
denoting of sort of writing neural nets
and various other models as block
diagrams and I'm using three different
types of symbols here or for really the
bubbles represent variables the bubbles
that I've filled up represent variables
that are observed so X is an observed
variable is the input to your system so
you observe it on the training set and
the test set and whatever Y bar is a
computed variable so it's it's something
that's just you know produced by a
deterministic function you can just
compute from the observe variable
through a deterministic function so Y
similarly is an observed variable
because on the or it's observed on the
training sites it's not observed on the
test set but during training it's
observed and then you have two types of
functional modules one type is those
kind of blue round shaped modules which
represent deterministic functions and
the the round side indicates in which
direction it's easy to compute okay so
here you can compute Y bar from X it's
considerably more complicated to compute
X from Y bar
if I give you a white bar but you have a
hard time giving me an X that
corresponds to it okay and then you have
another type of module which are usually
used to represent cost functions
represented by squares red squares to
make them more visible in this case and
they have an implicit output which is a
scalar output a single number and they
can take multiple inputs and basically
compute a single number usually a
distance between the inputs or something
similar to that
so with also basic symbols you can you
know you can represent sort of standard
supervised learning systems for those of
you who are familiar with graphical
models this this is a similar notation
that is used in what's called factor
graphs where the squares where factors
factor graphs don't have those
deterministic functions because they
don't care about in which you know which
way dependencies can be computed but in
our case it's really important okay so
loss functions so loss functions are
things that we minimize during training
and these two types of rust is the per
sample loss so in this case L of X Y W
so you give it a sample a pair x and y
and evaluate the parameter and it
computes just the scalar value okay in
all case here we use a very simple loss
which is just equal to the cost module
the output of the customer you Allah
will put on top over system this is kind
of the standard sort of supervised
learning paradigm here where the loss is
simply the average I mean the first
sample loss is just the output of the
cost function that we we put in it's not
always the case and then the loss that
we actually minimize to retraining is
the average loss over a training set so
training set s is a set of pairs X Y P Y
of P for P equals 0 to P minus 1 and the
overall loss which depends of course on
the training set and the parameter
values is the
average of the per sample loss overall
the samples
and I forgot to say in the first son
here it's X Y belongs to s so machine
learning is all about optimizing
functions most of the time minimizing
functions sometimes maximizing functions
occasionally finding Nash equilibria
between two functions as in the case of
Ganz but most of the time we minimize
functions and we do this with gradient
based methods not necessarily gradient
descent but gradient based methods what
is a gradient based method gradient
based method is a method that finds the
minimum of a function assuming that you
get easily compute the gradient of that
function so that assumes the function is
more or less differentiable it doesn't
actually have to be everywhere
differentiable technically it needs to
be continuous and it needs to be almost
everywhere differentiable otherwise you
run into trouble but it can have kinks
in it as long as they're not too nasty
and grainy descent of course as you
probably know consists in computing the
the gradient so you see a function here
at the top it's got a minimum at the top
right i drawn the lines of equal cost of
that function and the arrows that you
see are the gradient vectors the
gradient is pointing up okay at every
every location and the gradient is
always orthogonal to the lines of equal
cost okay
equal altitude if you want okay so when
in this set is like you know being in
the mountain in the fog and it's night
and you can't see anything but you want
to go down to the village and so you
look around you and you look for the
direction of steepest descent and you
take a step okay so the algorithm here
at the top the division vector which is
your position is replaced by the double
your current W vector minus some
constant times the gradient vector and
the gradient vector points up so when
you do - you're kind of walking downhill
in the direction of steepest descent
now this is if ADA is a scalar constant
but in sophisticated algorithms that can
actually be a matrix so if it's a matrix
if it's a positive semi definite matrix
it will still go down go downhill
except that not necessarily in the
direction of steepest descent in fact
the direction of steepest descent is not
necessarily the one you want to go to if
you have a situation like the one at the
top where the the value is a little Ella
gated the gradient actually does not
point towards the minimum it point
started you know off off center and so
it should go directly to the minimum you
don't want to follow the gradient you
want to be a little smarter than this
and by using sort of idea that all
matrices you can actually you could in
principle do this with so called second
order methods which are still gradient
based methods but they're kind of
impractical in most cases we'll talk
about some issues with this in a few
weeks now there are algorithms that are
not gradient based optimization
algorithms are not gradient based so
when your function is not differentiable
when it's like a golf course you know
it's flat and it's got a hole in it or
when it's kind of staircase like where
the gradient doesn't give you an
information useful information or when
it may be differentiable but you don't
know the function you don't you know you
don't write you didn't write the program
that actually computes it because that
function might might be the entire
environment around you then you cannot
compute the gradient efficiently ok so
then you have to resort to other methods
methods are called zeroth order methods
or gradient free methods and there's a
whole bunch of whole family of those
functions of those methods which I'm not
going to talk about ok at all
deep learning is all about gradient
based methods that said if you're
interested in reinforcement learning
most of reinforcement learning actually
uses
great at estimation without the gradient
what you want is I don't know you want
to get a robot to learn to ride a bike
and once in a while the robot Falls and
you don't have a gradient for the
objective function that says don't fall
or the objective function that measures
how long you the bike stays up without
falling nobody tells you what to do to
minimize that cost function right so you
try things you can't compute a gradient
of that function okay so in RL your cost
function is not differentiable most of
the time but the network that computes
the output that goes into the
environment is differentiable okay so
from that point on that's that's great
in this only the cost is not
differentiable
okay so there'll be a situation like the
diagram I showed earlier imagine here
that G is differentiable you can compute
the gradient of the output of G with
respect to the parameters and its input
and everything but C is not
differentiable in fact it's completely
unknown the only thing you know about C
is that if you give it a Y bar and Y it
tells you the value but doesn't give you
the gradient okay that's kind of what RL
is there are the things about RL okay
but that's the basic difference between
reinforcement learning and supervised
learning yeah
well the reward is just the output of C
that's all okay so it's use a black box
and what you get is the output of C you
don't you don't get a Y either right so
you're not being told what the correct
answer is you just talk about black box
you give it a white bar and it gives
your sink that's it
you can't compute the gradient of C with
respect to Y bar that's right so what
you do is you change Y by a little bit
and you see the C go up or down
two goes down you kind of reinforce that
he goes up you do something else okay so
basically you're telling the system how
good it is doing without turning it the
correct answer and it doesn't have
access to acquit yeah
okay so what that tells you is that RL
is horribly inefficient right because
you don't have a gradient so you have to
try you know if the if the output Y bar
is row dimensional then you know it's
okay right you can you can try to make
it larger smaller things like that but
it's not too bad if Y bar is a high
dimensional vector there's like such a
huge space to search it's probably no
way you're gonna find an optimal value
for it unless you try lots and lots of
different times right so that's a huge
problem with RL and I would take weeks
in RL actually I'm not gonna talk about
hourly this course actually except today
maybe but a very properly technique in
RL is so-called actual critic methods
and a critic method basically consists
in having a second C module which you
know which is a trainable module and you
train you see your own C module which is
differentiable to approximate the one to
approximate the cost function the value
function that you get the rewards the
reward function you get so reward is the
inverse of a cost okay so I mean this is
a negative of a cost and you get more
like your punishment actually but so
then that that's a way
of making the cost function
differentiable or at least approximating
it by a differentiable function and that
you can just use back pop so the you
know AC a AC and a AAA C are versions of
this actor critic Adventures actor
critic etc okay right so what you have
to know how to do is compute the
gradient of your per sample you of your
objective function with respect to the
parameters in practice we'll use the
caste gradient as you probably aware so
instead of computing the gradient of the
entire objective function which is the
average of all samples we just take one
sample compute the loss L Big L compute
the gradient of these charts with
respect to their parameters and then
take one step in the negative gradient
direction okay so that's the the second
formula here W is replaced by W minus
some step size times the gradient of the
per sample loss function with respect to
the parameter for a given sample XP YP
yep yep okay so in practice people use
batches so instead of doing this on a
single sample so first of all if you do
this on a single sample you're going to
get a very noisy trajectory you're gonna
get trajectory like the one you see here
at the bottom where instead of the
parameter vector directly kind of going
downhill it's going to oscillate so some
people say it should not be called SGD
which means to get the gradient descent
because it's not actually a descent
algorithm should be called stochastic
gradient optimization but it's
stochastic so it's very noisy every
sample you get is going to
in a different direction it's just the
average that pulls you towards the
minimum of the average so it looks
inefficient but in fact it's actually
fast it's much faster than batch
gradient at least in the context of
machine learning when the samples had
some redundancy between them and it goes
faster to do stochastic gradient so to
the the question of batching so what
people do most of the time is that they
compute the average of the gradient over
a batch of samples not a single sample
and then do one step and the only reason
for doing this this has nothing to do
with you know algorithmic convergence
efficacy or do you think the only reason
for doing this is because the kind of
hardware we that is given to us there
are is our disposal GPUs and multi-core
CPUs is more efficient if you if you
have batches it's easier to paralyze so
you get more efficient computation use
of your hardware if you use batches it's
a bad reason for batching but we have no
choice until you know someone builds a
piece of hardware that actually is
properly designed the reason we have to
do this again is for is because the
chips that we have you know in DDR GPUs
are so you know heavily paralyzed but
they depart lies in a simple way and the
simplest way to paralyze is to batch yes
yeah but okay so so here is why
stochastic gradient is is better right
if I give you a million samples but in
these million samples I actually only
have actually 10,000 different samples
and I repeat those 10,000 samples 100
times and I shuffle them and I give you
this training sample and I give you it's
a million samples you don't know it's
actually only 10,000 samples repeated
100 times if you use batch gradient you
can
compute a hundred times the same
quantities and average them so gonna
spend how many times more computation
than necessary well she used to catch
the gradient by the time you've seen
20,000 samples you voted on two
iterations your two passes through your
entire training set okay so it'll be at
least a hundred times more efficient so
the question is you know what's you know
how much can you average in a batch
without using you know efficiency in the
redundancy and some people have done
experiments with this is some empirical
evidence that the number of samples that
you can put in a batch is roughly equal
to the number of categories you have if
you do classification between one and
two times the number of categories you
have so if you train on imagenet you
have 1,000 categories you can you can
have batches up to about two thousand
and beyond this you start losing
conversion speed that means are
completely random basically I mean that
never occurs right because think about
okay think about the refirming scenario
that you can be that training set and
what I do is that I split it in half and
I use the first as a training set and
the second one the second half as the
validation set if there is zero we
doesn't see in your in your in your set
that means my machine is not gonna work
at all right it's not gonna be able to
generalize on the second half right so
if there is any possibility of
generalization there has to be some
redundancy okay so let's start
and talk about traditional neural nets
okay traditional neural nets are
basically interspersed layers of linear
operations and point where's nonlinear
operations so the linear operation you
have an input vector you compute a
weighted sum of that vector with a bunch
of weights and in this case here we have
six inputs with three hidden units in
the first layer so there's three
different sets of ways with which we
compute weighted sums of the six inputs
the conceptually the operation to go
from the input the six dimensional input
vector to the three dimensional weighted
sum is just a matrix vector
multiplication right take the input
vector multiplied by a matrix form by
the weights it's going to be a three by
six matrix right and so you multiply
this by six dimensional vector you get a
three dimensional vector okay so that's
the first type of operation in a case
called neural net and the second type of
operation is that you take all the
components of the the vector the
weighted sums and you pass them through
simple nonlinearities in this case this
is called a value it's called a half
wave rectification in engineering you
know there's different names for it but
basically it's the positive part
mathematically so it's equal to identity
when X when the argument is positive and
is equal to zero and the argument is
negative and then you repeat the process
so the third stage is again a linear
stage multiply that three dimensional
vector by a matrix in this case a two by
three matrix you get a two dimensional
vector pass the components two
nonlinearities okay I could insert a two
layer Network because I think what
matters are the pairs linear non linear
okay so most people recall this a two
layer Network some people recall it's a
3 layer Network because they count the
variables but I don't think that's fair
you do this but you know what you don't
want to do this
if there is no nonlinearities in the in
the middle as I said last week you might
as well have a single layer because the
product of two linear functions is a
linear function and so you can collapse
them into a single one basically a
single matrix that is the product of the
two matrices okay so here it is a little
more detail the sum of unit I is so s I
which is a weighted sum for unit I is is
the sum over all the predecessors of I
which is denoted up of I okay so the J
index goes over all the predecessors of
I of W IJ x zj where Z J is the output
the J side pull from the previous layer
this is a sort of stack you know kind of
regular layered neural net and then you
take a particular si and you pass it
through one of those nonlinear functions
F and you get Zi
talk about early computer gradients and
things like this
and these two forms of it okay there is
an intuitive form that I'm going to
explain right now which does not even
require you to know what a derivative is
funnily enough and then there is a
slightly more general form there's an
even more general form that maybe I'll
talk about next week okay so let's say
we have a big network we have a cost
function and so or thing has an X on a Y
and it's gonna cost coming out but in
fact you don't need to make this
assumption the only assumption you need
to make is that you have some primary
choice function that produces a scalar
on the output that's it
okay and somewhere in that network you
have a nonlinear function H I called it
F in the previous slide but i call it h
here so it takes a one of those weighted
sum s you pass it through this H
function and then it produces one of
those Z Z variables okay I'm not putting
an index here because you know it's just
I'm taking one particular you know one
of those functions outside of the
network and I do the the rest of the
network as kind of a black box so let's
assume that okay so we're going to use
chain rule chain rule if you remember
from kindergarten okay high school okay
college if you have two functions that
fill each other your G of H of s and you
want to differentiate it so G of H of s
prime is equal to the derivative of G at
point H of s multiplied by the
derivative of H at Point s all right
this going back
okay but if you want through you know
couple years of college you can write
this the way Newton wrote it or earlier
or whatever with the infinitesimal
quantities so you can write D C over D s
which means the derivative at 0 s by 2 s
is equal to D C over DZ times DZ over
the s ok so it's the derivative of C
with respect to Z Z multiplied by the
derivative of Z with respect to s and
the nice the nice reason for writing it
like this is that it's obvious you can
simplify by DZ right you have dizzy at
the bottom and at the top and so by
simplifying by DZ this is the second
line you get DC over the s ok so you
kind of split the derivative by having
certain intermediate variable that you
put at the bottom and at the top right
it's very simple manipulation simple
equally palacios now DZ over D s is just
the derivative of Z with respect to s
with Z is equal to H of s so that's just
H prime of s ok so D Co VDS is equal to
DT over D G times H prime of s so if if
someone gives you the derivative of the
cost function with respect to Z you
multiplied by the derivative of your
nonlinear function and you get the
derivative of the cost function with
respect to s ok so imagine you have a
chain of those functions in your network
you can back propagate by multiplying by
the derivatives of all those H functions
H functions when after the other all the
way back to the to the bottom ok so
basically if you want to compute a
gradient
you basically have to use a network that
looks very much like this one except you
have signals that go backwards and
wherever you had an H function what you
have now is derivative coming from the
top ok so scalar just the same as e
you're multiplied by the derivative of
the H function and then you get the
derivative of the cost function with
respect to the input variable to H which
is s
so basically what you have now is a
basically a transform network that
computes your gradient okay now you can
convince yourself of this because if you
don't really sort of completely grok
chain world which I hope you do but
imagine that you are you know twiddling
s by little okay we're going to we're
going to perturb s by Diaz
so as we go through h h as a stroke
which is s prime of s so Z is going to
be perturbed by D s times that
derivative right D s times H prime of s
okay this is what is being written here
for tubing s by D s were perturb Z by DZ
equal D s times H prime of s this will
perturb CV by the small perturbation DZ
times the gradient of I mean the
derivative of C with respect to Z right
which is DC or dizzy so basically we get
that DC equals DZ the perturbation of Z
so patch will show C is equal to the
perturbation with Z DZ times the
gradient of other derivative of single
spec to Z okay but we've computed this
DZ before we know is the s time H prime
of s so we just substitute in and then
we pass the s on the other side and we
get simply that DT over D is equal to C
over DZ times H prime of s okay we just
we derive chain rule okay I've done
nothing more than really IV general but
it's a lot more intuitive if you think
of it in terms of you know twitting
things around and sometimes it's useful
when you're writing the backup function
for a module to think in those terms
okay because sometimes it's easier to
think about it in those terms than to
actually write down the equations
alright now we had two types of modules
in orbit you know or you know on that
the other one is a linear module okay
and for this one I'm gonna again use the
internet work as a black
except for just three connections going
from AZ variable to a bunch of s
variables okay so an SRO is a weighted
sum so s 0 for example is going to take
Z the Z at the bottom here by
multiplying it but it's only W which I
call W 0 okay
I draw up all indices that are annoying
and so then I can ask again the question
if I if I twiddle Z by how much will CB
twiddled ok so if I twiddle Z s 0 is
going to be twiddle by Z times W 0 right
because Z is multiplied by W 0 so if I
so it W 0 is is 2 and I twiddle Z by by
DZ the output after the weight is going
to be twice okay it's gonna be trolled
by twice the value but now Z actually
influences several variables in this
case 3 so it's also going to cause a
probation for s of 1 and s of to the
prohibition for s oh one is going to be
d ZW 1 and for s of 2 is going to be d
ZW 2 okay so the overall perturbation
now okay so so we get D Z times W 0 that
is the prohibition for a 0 DZ times W 1
for s 1 DZ times W 2 4 is 2 but now s 0
s 1 and s 2 are going to influence C and
the question is by how much so C is
going to vary by whatever a 0 was
varying times the derivative of C with
respect to a 0 right but also C is also
going to vary because s 1 is varying and
also because s 2 is varying if the
variations are small enough then the
overall value
variation is just the sum of the three
variations okay
and so what you have here at the bottom
is that the entire variation of the cost
is going to be equal to the variation of
Z multiplied by W zero multiplet which
is the version of a zero and then you're
going to have to multiply that by the
derivative of C with respect to a 0
which is DC over da 0 ok so what you see
here at the last in the last equation is
exactly that and and you have to sum the
contributions from the three components
ok so this year which is easy and is DC
over D s 0 times W 0 plus DC over the s
1 times W 1 plus GC over the as 2 times
W 2
okay when you have a branch like this
you perturb the input variable all
branches or perturb and you have to sum
up the results on the cost function okay
which you assume you know others are the
DC over the whatever variables any
question is it clear Iko principle
okay what does that mean like look at
this formula here it says if I have the
gradient of or if I have the derivative
of C the derivative derivative of C with
respect to s 0 s 1 and s 2 okay all
three of them then I compute the
weighted sum of those derivatives with
the weights going up but I'm using them
going down and that gives me the
derivative of the cost function with
respect to Z which feeds those three
weights so basically when you back
propagate through a neural net you
compute weighted sum of gradients using
the weights backwards ok all right so
this is to give a little bit of
intuition but there is a much more
general general formulation for this
before we do this let's let's write it
this way okay do it one step at a time
so conceptually you know on that the way
you want to see it is more something
like this where you have at least a
traditional neural net we have an input
variable you multiply the input variable
by the first matrix W 0 that gives you s
1 and then pass that through a
non-linearity that gives you Z 1 then
multiply that by the weight matrix W 1
that gives us two paths out to a
non-linearity that gives you Z 2 linear
again bah-bah-bah how many how many how
many layer neural net is this three yes
layer is gonna repair in your nonlinear
right most modern neural Nets don't
actually have clear linear nonlinear
separations they're like more complex
things okay so so SK plus one basically
equals W K times Z K where wk is a
matrix DK is a vector XK plus 1 is a
vector and then Z K equals h HK where H
is kind of application of the scalar h
function to every component so if you
write this in Python
you write something like this there's
many ways to write it in pi torch you
can you can write it from scratch she
can write it in a functional way or you
can write it this way which is more like
object-oriented and it kind of hides a
video complexity for you so your torch
you for import an end from torch you
make a sort of an input which is some
300 310 sir you can't how many elements
it has and that's going to be the size
of your input layer we're going to turn
it into a vector okay but not yet and
then you define a class for your neural
net so the the constructor is going to
just initialize three linear layers so
linear layers need to in this case these
separate objects because they contain a
vector for the parameter the values
don't need to be separate objects could
do not actually have parameters okay so
that's the complexity that's hidden in
those NN linear so an engineer actually
does a little bit more than just
multiplying the matrix it also adds a
bias factor but that's okay so you
initialize those layers with the right
sizes that you passed as argument to the
constructor and then you define a
forward function which is you know how
you can compute the output as a function
of the input and so the the first one
here X dot view minus one just flattens
the input tensor into its into a vector
and then you apply the n zero module to
X you get s1 then apply the value the
non-linearity to s1 you get Z one etc
etc and then you return s3 okay and the
beauty of pie charts which Alfredo will
explain to you they hatch tomorrow is
that you don't need to worry about
computing the gradient because as you
you've written the forward function and
patrasche knows what this looks like and
he knows how to back propagate gradient
to it it knows how to transform the
graph that corresponds to your forward
function into a graph that corresponds
to the back function so you're not too
worried about it
but you still need to know how to keep
your gradients because sometimes you
have to write your own module you invent
this new type of neural net that's got
this new you know like you know multi
head multi tail
you know memory attention STM whatever
you know you have to write your own
thing and you basically you might have
to write your own and CUDA kernel or
whatever right but it's pretty simple
yes so as I said if you don't have a
non-linearity the whole thing is linear
so it doesn't there's no point having
layers okay now you have to think you
know what is the simplest non-linearity
you can think of it's gonna be a point
where is you know component or as
non-linearity was it was the simplest
component wise non-linearity you can
think of something that has a single
kink
now the funny thing is we're talking
about gradient baserunning this is not
even differentiable right because it's
got a kink but if you're a mathematician
and you obsessive-compulsive about it
you would call this not gradient but a
sub gradient but you know how many
mathematicians are there here yes
there's several sub gradient so here a
function that has a kink in it at this
point any slope that is between this one
and that one is correct it's fine okay
all of those are good sub gradients and
so the question is you should use
something in the kind of somewhere in
the middle or just zero it doesn't
matter because it's just one point so it
has no impact no practical impact
okay so here's the strategy more general
form we're going from the kind of
specific to the strategy more general so
here's a form of chain rule for modules
that may have multiple outputs and
multiple inputs or may have inputs that
are vectors and outputs that are vectors
okay I don't I don't give them different
symbols here the the basic formula DC
over dzf in this case equal this here it
is e G times DZ g or DZ f holds right
this is the same chain rule formula that
we were previously for scalar functions
it also applies to vector functions okay
but there's one thing that we need to
remember the gradient of the scalar
function with respect to a vector is a
vector of the same size as the vector
with respect to which you differentiate
make sure if you write it this way and
you want the notations to be consistent
it's a row vector it's not a column
vector anymore okay so we'll take a
scalar function which depends on the
vector therefore a column vector
differentiate this scalar function with
respect to the to this column vector
what you get is a row vector that's the
gradient it's not the gradient
technically the gradient is once you
transpose it but it's DC over DZ F
that's the that's the notation and you
can see that it kind of checks out so
let's imagine that Z G is a vector
column vector so of size DG by one and
ZF is a column vector of size DF by one
then this little general equation here
gives you a world vector size DF is
equal to
vector of size DG multiplied by a matrix
who is number of rows is DG and the real
columns is DF ok and of course the size
the last size of the vector and the
first size of the matrix have to match
if you want this product to work out so
a more convenient form for this would be
to kind of transpose everything to say
this here with ETR transpose which is
now a column vector is equal to the
transpose of the product here and that
would be the transpose of DZ over DZ f
times the transpose of d c over d GG and
that would be kind of a more convenient
form of writing it but it's kind of
simpler this way Okin system okay so
what's this funny animal here DZ g over
DZ f so we have little neural net here
that has two modules in it
FNG the output of F the of the F module
is ZF and the output of the G model is e
G okay and basically we want the
gradient of the cost function with
respect to Z F we assume we know the
gradient of this cost function is
affected Z G we know how to back
propagate to see and to compute the
gradient with respect to Z F if we know
the greater respect to Z G we need to
multiply by this matrix d zg / DZ f
which is called the Jacobian matrix of G
with respect to its input okay G has two
arguments so we can differentiate it
with respect to Z or respect to W which
is going to differentiate it with
respect to Z okay what is this matrix so
the entry I J of that matrix the
Jacobian matrix is equal to the partial
derivative of the eyes
I put okay the ice component of the
output vector of the G module with
respect to the jth component of the
input vector
so if I twiddle the J's input is gonna
make all the output to twiddle and that
basically is an entire column of the
Jacobian matrix okay
that's back problem right so if you have
a network composed of a cascade of
modules you just keep multiplying by the
Jacobian matrix of all the modules going
down and you get all the gradient
suspect to all the eternal variables now
you actually need two sets of of
gradients you need the gradient so
respect to the Statesville so the
gradients with respect to the weights
and there's a as I said a module that
has parameters has two Jacobian matrices
it has one with respect to its input
state and another one with respect to
its parameters okay so you have the two
equations here so let's say now you have
kind of a slightly more general neural
net which is a stack of you know many
modules each module is called FK so okay
it's kind of an index for that module in
its input is ZK and it's parameters WK
and the output is you know ZK plus 1 so
ZK plus 1 equals F KO z k WK very simple
so how do i compute DC / g zk which is
the gradient of the cost function or
whatever function you want to minimize
with respect to the input of module ZK
assuming I know GC / gz k plus 1 already
you just multiplied by the Jacobian
matrix of the module care which is G ZK
plus 1 over G ZK or in other words the
FK of Z k WK respect to z k okay so it's
just chain rule again D Z over G ZK
equals this
z k equals DC or DZ k plus one which i
assume i know x the Jacobian matrix of f
k with respect to z k second line is
same thing with respect to w vc over DW
k is equal to DC over DZ k plus 1 which
already had at the top and then DZ k
plus 1 over d WK which is the Jacobian
matrix of the F function with respect to
its weights to its parameters
whatever they are that's all there is to
back part we okay
any question
she's a little cute example was so
Michael Crete
so let's say we've you know one of those
simple functions here G of X W we don't
know what's inside but it's okay and it
goes to a cost function it's a graph and
through this manipulation of you know
multiplying by Jacobian matrices we can
transform this graph into the graph that
will compute the gradients going
backwards and so things like by torsion
circle do this automatically for you you
write a function it turns it into a
graph and then there is something that
turns its graph into the derivative
graph if you want that back propagates
the gradient so in this case here the
the gradient graph looks like the one at
the at the right when you start with one
at the top and then you compute the
Jacobian of C with respect to y bar you
multiply this one number by this
Jacobian Jacobian is actually a vector
okay it's a gradient it's a row vector
and that's DC over dy bar then you
multiply that but it could be enough G
with respect to its weight and you get
the gradient of respect to the weights
that's what you need to train so that's
an example of you know automatic
transformation that's what odigo a does
now where becomes complicated is when
the the graph the architecture of the
graph is not fixed but is data dependent
so let's imagine that depending on the
value of x you have a test in your
neuron that code that decides that you
know if X is a vector that is longer
than a certain length then you do
something to do one thing and it is
shorter you do another thing you know
then you're gonna have kind of
the condition Intergraph depending on
the input right you still need to
generate the graph of backpropagation
she have loops it becomes complicated
you can still do it yeah yeah it it
usually doesn't work very well if the
number of loops that you have is more
than say 50 and same 50 it could be 20
right it depends and you've probably
heard of STM and what's special about it
STM compared to regular recurrent Nets
is one way of basically making them work
for longer than like five but they don't
work very well past twenty years old the
point is that you can have a variable
number of steps it's it's specified by
program and it could be variable depends
on the size of the input a lot of them
you all know some people use nowadays a
variable size X's could be a variable
size multi-dimensional array and that
means Genie has variable size inside and
you can have you know kind of
complicated he's going on there so again
in terms of the the sizes that those
things take so DC / GW is is a row
vector which is 1 by n where n is the
number of components of W DC / dy bar is
1 by M where m is the dimension of the
output and dy bar DW is number of number
of rows is the number of outputs of G
and the number of columns is the
dimension of W which is n so it takes
out
so so fine okay now what kind of modules
are we using in neural net so as I said
the linear and rare modules or
non-linear point-wise non-linearity
modules are just two examples of things
that we use to build neural nets but
what you build deep learning systems in
general but it's tons of and tons I mean
if you look at the Python documentation
there is like a huge list of them of
such modules and the reason why you need
it a lot of them I mean most of them are
kind of can be built out of kind of
smaller like more elementary functions
but the reason why they are pre-built is
because first they have a name but and
the debug but also because they
optimized so sometimes you can kind of
write you know CUDA kernels directly or
you know they're generated by a compiler
or something so but here's a bunch of
elementary modules and I'm not sure I'm
going to be able to use my
okay let's start with a duplicate module
so what in the duplicate module is say
it's a module that takes a single takes
you know it's basically a Y connector
okay you want two people to listen to
music on your iPhone you need one of
those Y cables so the first output is
equal to the input and the second output
is also equal to the input okay
y1 equals x y2 equals x so you think you
know you would think that you don't even
either with your like this but you
actually do sometimes in fact in
patrasche this kind of implicit but but
you need to make it explicit sometimes
so whenever you have a wire that splits
into 2 or n on the way back the
gradients get summed okay and it's
exactly the same situation that I
explained earlier in fact you can
decompose this video module that I
explain here you can think of this Z
variable spitting into three wires as
one of those branch modules and as the
three wire converge you have to sum the
gradients okay which we figured out but
you can you can sort of build this into
this speed module just duplicate module
or triplicate or n ticket whatever it is
okay so whatever you copy a variable we
are whatever you use available in
multiple places you need to sum the
gradients again the auto grading in PI
tortoises for you but remember this so
add so if you have two variables and you
sum them up we
this guy the output which will by the
same quantity for you to love this guy
the output will twiddle by the same
quantity what that means is that the
gradient of whatever function you want
to minimize with respect to the output
of a sum is equal to the equal when you
have the gradient of the cost function
with respect to the some weight is the
gradient with respect to each of the two
branches that you added up it's actually
equal for both branches okay so if you
have a connection going this way and you
get a gradient from the top you just
copy the gradient okay it's because you
get the same influence from both sides
no it's independent of the value of the
inputs if you think about it but it's
pretty obvious actually let me try this
can you be able to do this
okay
this work ha only works if I mirror my
screen because I can't write on the
screen that doesn't exist okay hang on
with me for just a minute here know what
I want
okay
oops oh wow
okay all right
here we go sorry about that let's go to
a place that actually works okay you see
this works so so if y equals x 1 plus x
2 DC over the X 1 let's say is equal to
D C over D Y D Y over the X 1 okay this
we assume we know how much is this one
and of course the Y of the X 2 is also 1
okay so there you have it this here the
X 1 equals to C over D Y is your really
X to equal this you're really why just
take this already why copy it and you're
done
max that's an interesting one so y
equals max of XY next to this you're
ready x1 equal this your D Y D Y over
the X 1 right let's just chain rule
what is the worry DX 1 yep and otherwise
it's 1
yes correct so in fact you can
completely understand this graphically
basically you have X 1 this again yes
yes yes right so the answer was D Y DX 1
0 if X 2 is larger than x1 and is 1 if X
1 is larger than X 2 but intuitively is
very simple if you have variable X 1 and
variable X 2 basically the output
this max module is basically just a
switch okay I'm putting an arrow here
but it's not an arrow it's a switch okay
I can move this switch from left to
right okay I can choose to connect x1 to
Y or to connect X 2 to y now once I've
decided on which side I connect is just
a wire right regardless on how high
chose to put the switch in one position
of the other in this case I use max okay
but it's just a switch that I decide to
put on one side or the other when I
decide to put it on one side then I've
just connected x1 to Y and it's just a
wire so x2 if I twiddle it has no
influence on the output therefore the
gradient of the cost function is fed to
x2 is 0 okay and the gradient of the
cost function with respect to x1 is of
course equal to the gradient of the cost
function inspector why because it's just
a wire it's the same variable really
okay
so that generalizes to a switch a switch
of multiple variables so are the many
valuable I have if the output is
determined by you know a switch that I
can move to one of the input variables
then when I back propagate I just
propagate through the variable that was
connected and the other ones just get
zero okay it's easier to
draw this way than to actually write the
math you have to use Delta functions and
stuff is okay knocks off max that's a
fun one
oh I have to use any page but next page
actually doesn't go to the next page
okay so softmax is module where the ad
put why i is equal to e to the X I so
it's a module with which I should not
draw this way should draw this way and
it has as many outputs as it has inputs
I'm pulling this the Y I and is the X J
let's say okay or X whatever so softmax
is this okay it's a very convenient way
of transforming a bunch of numbers into
a bunch of positive numbers between 0 &
1 that sum to 1 okay when I take the
exponential so X the X J's can be any
number when I take the exponential of
those numbers I get positive numbers and
I normalize by their sum so what I get
is a bunch of numbers that are between 0
& 1 & sum to 1 which some people call a
probability distribution okay so you can
interpret why I as a vector of
probabilities over the discrete set of
outcomes what is
dog stuff max so locks off max is oops
no what I want you to do it's the log of
that so you get the log of the stuff at
the top minus the log of the stuff at
the bottom right so you get the log of
exponential X I and that's going to be X
I and there's a mistaken and then you
get the log of the sum of you get minus
the log of this some of the
Exponential's of X J's right so that
will give us X I minus log of sum over J
of e to the X J let's call log surf max
now the guy who invented softmax in 1989
or so or maybe 88 I don't remember is a
gentleman by the name of john vidal a
from britain and he regretted calling it
softmax he said it should have been
called soft egg max but it's too late
people call it soft max so here's an
interesting exercise for you I'm not
going to tell you how you back propagate
through this okay but I want you to do
the calculation it's a very good
exercise so laps off meg is actually a
module in Python but do it on your own
it's a perfect exercise
so basically compute DC or by DX K
assuming that you know although DC
already why eyes okay
so you're gonna have a bunch of detail
with you eyes so here you only have one
output actually but it's okay so what I
say there is only one Y I and you know
the gradient of the loss with respect to
this why I what is the gradient of the
loss with respect to all of the X K's
that's good exercise is it an official
homework it's an official homework
tonight okay it's more than just an
exercise you can find the answer but
it's more fun to kind of you know I mean
you're not you don't you don't run as
much if you don't kind of try about
yourself you should just look the answer
okay so the softmax analog is a
combination of modules that is very
commonly used in a multi-class
classification right so you may take an
all-night the last module would be a
soft max so we'd normalize all the
outputs make them positive made them
look like probabilities and what you
want is you want to maximize the
probability that the model gives to the
correct answer okay so you know the
correct answer is
bird bird is number four in your
categories you want the fourth I put
yourself Mac to be as high as possible
okay so that's the BB dog soft max now
if you separate this into things so if
you have soft Max and then you take the
log of the output as your cost function
the log of the correct output on your
cost function you get a you get
numerical issues because you don't get
log of zero okay so as the score gets
very very small the log kind of diverges
and you get sort of numerical problems
so we're better off writing locks off
max directly as a single module because
then that numerical issue disappears
okay that's a good question in fact it's
a very good question for the next 20
minutes not just the next 20 minutes
actually I stupidly put my pin back did
I what did you do my pen I have no idea
what I did with a pen it's here okay
okay so let's say you're gonna have any
on that and it's gonna take an X
variable and then it's gonna have w0 and
then value and then w1 okay and now we
get a bunch of scores and we're gonna
turn this into a score between 0 & 1 now
this network has only one output and so
we can only do a two class
classification and the module we're
going to put here is the sigmoid
function also called logistic function
and so this function is H of discredit s
since we've called this s before 1 over
1 plus exponential minus s okay so this
function when s is very large this
exponential is equal to close to 0 and
so H is equal to 1 and when s is very
small or highly negative then this
exponential becomes very large and so
the overall function is you
okay so that function is like this and
here it's 0.5 and the asymptote here is
plus 1 and here is just 0 a 0.5 is
unreadable ok so I could just take the
output here which I can call Y bar and
plug this through some cost function
which I compare with y okay now so Y
would be also a binary variable 0 1 now
what what do this cost function what
should it do I could use square error
right so C could be equal to the
difference between y and y bar squared
sounds perfectly reasonable doesn't work
very well
reason it doesn't work very well is that
the is that the sigmoid and people you
know in the early days of neural nets in
the 1980s we're doing this very commonly
and the network wouldn't converging I
would say neural nets don't work they
were just doing it wrong
so the problem that you have here is
that if Y is equal to 1 for one class
and 0 for the other class the system
wants to get the output equal to 1 and
it can't because it's an asymptote so it
tries to make the weights that we won
very very large so that it gets to 1 or
to 0 it has to make the weighted sum
enormous you know if it wants to get
close to the desired output the bell the
gradient is very small right because the
derivative of that sigmoid that Sigma is
very flat there so when you back
propagate
the gradient is basically zero because
the Sigma is flat so you get the
saturation problem so some people like
said you know back in the old days one
of two things either you set your
targets in between so not at the
asymptotes or you use a different loss
okay so so basically you say here is the
sigmoid function the target for a
category one is going to be at
I don't know point eight and the target
for category 2 is going to be at point
two so there those would be a table and
so the weights won't go to infinity and
you won't have those problems but here's
another idea and the other idea is just
take the log of it okay
take the log so if you think about this
the zero function here it's actually a
softmax it's a soft max between two
variables one of which is equal to minus
x the other one is equal to 1 and what
you're getting is the surf max output
from from the input that's always equal
to 1 okay then you write this function
in another way I'm going to multiply the
top and the bottom by e to the S okay so
I get e to the s divided by e to the S
plus e to the x times e to the minus s
and that's 1 okay this is our faqs it's
off max where when input is 1 the other
one is s and what I'm looking at is the
S the output corresponding to the s
input
so when Sigma it's just you know softmax
is just a generalization is assimilated
for multiple outputs now if you take a
lot of this
you get s minus log of 1 plus e to the S
okay
the question is and again this is a
special occasion softmax with only two
inputs where one is equal to one one of
the one of the two inputs is equal to
one okay so the effect of the log like
look at this this function here this
function looks like this where when s is
very large the 1 doesn't count in the
sum and so you basically a vlog of
exponential s which is just s right so
for large s is just the identity
function and for small s the 1 dominates
and so it slope 1 which is 0 as we get 0
it's kind of like a soft really kind of
thing but the point is it doesn't
saturate so you don't get those
vanishing gradient issue
yes we have a log in front so log E
power s is s oh yeah I mean sure I mean
if you could do as far as s then I was
just talking about the second term yeah
yeah I mean s - this is kind of the
other way around yeah absolutely yeah
you should take the entire the entire
function it's it's the exact opposite
okay do you have softmax also as one of
the exercises yeah right okay all right
so let's end with a few tricks practical
tricks and you will you'll see more of
them tomorrow and as you start playing
with back prop so the idea of using
value instead of hyperbole tension so
hyperbole tension is just like the Sigma
8 I just showed except that it's
multiplied by 2 and you subtract 1 so it
it goes from minus 1 to 1 instead of 0
to 1 but it's essentially the same shape
huh
yeah we talked about it last week
and they're both putting out of favor
value tends to work much better when you
have many layers and probably the reason
is that it's it's scale invariant in the
sense that or scale equivalent if if the
input is if you multiply the input by 2
the output we multiplied by 2 but
otherwise unchanged right it's got only
one kink and so it has no scale to it
whereas if you had 2 Kings then you know
the input has to have a particular the
onions to kind of fit those 2 kings in
the right place so people will use read
you the use cross-entropy does for
classification lock softmax is a special
case a simple special case of
cross-entropy laws we'll come back to
that yes
cross interview was like definitely
expect the logs on taxes but it's super
easy right yeah you want to use well so
long soft max not soft max definitely if
you feed it to a question Cheerios
function it expects outputs from a lock
soft max notice off length if you don't
know this yet you might waste a lot of
time in stochastic gradient on mini
batches we talked about this before you
shuffle the training samples we've used
the casi gradient the order of the
examples matters if you have I don't
know a 10-way classification doing
endless try to classifying the ten
digits from 0 to 9 if you put all the
zeros and all the ones then all the
tools and etc it's not going to work
because what's going to happen is that
in the first few examples of zeros the
system will adapt the biases of the last
layer to just produce the correct output
and we'll never learn what a zero looks
like and then you show one and it's
going to take just a few samples for it
to adapt to biases so that it learns to
produce one without actually looking at
the input and it's going to keep doing
this for eons and eons and it's never
gonna converge so you absolutely need to
shuffle the examples in the case of n
days but it's true also for a lot of
others
you probably want in a mini batch as I
said before it may be that you want
examples of all the categories if you
really want to use an e batch use
samples from different categories and if
you don't use a mini batch just you know
have samples of different categories one
after the other there is debate as to
whether you need to change the order of
the samples at every pass through the
samples it's not an entirely clear some
people claim it's better if you don't
some people people claim it's better if
you do with you know various theoretical
arguments for it you need to normalize
the input variables so if you look at
standard code that people publish for
training on imagenet or speech
recognition or whatever the first
operation they do is that
they normalize the inputs what do they
do they
so an image is really going to be three
planes are G and D okay so it's think of
it as a three-dimensional array where
the first dimension is color plane and
the other two dimensions are space or
sometimes the other way around
sometimes the channel is last but it is
better to think of it this way
so what you do is you take each of those
guys so let's say blue you compute the
mean of all the all the variables in
this blue image and you do this for
every single image in your training set
okay take the entire training set or a
good chunk of it and compute the mean of
all the blue
inputs for the entire training set that
gives you a single scalar right let's
call it MB so it's the mean of all the
Blues okay so interesting you can do the
same you can compute the standard
deviation where I compute the variance
of all the Blues and take the square
root that's substandard deviation Sigma
B you know same for green
same for red okay so we get six numbers
six scalar values and now what you do is
you take whatever you see an image you
take the all component IJ and to
normalize it you replace it by itself
minus the mean divided by the standard
deviation or the max of the standard
deviation and some small quantity so it
doesn't blow up what does that do for
you it normalizes the contrast and
normal eye and it makes the variant zero
this is good for various reasons in fact
it's a good idea to have variables
inside of a neural net that are zero
mean and unit variance or kind of
variance there are more or less all the
same of course you do this also for the
green and blue yeah across across many
images it's a single mean yeah I mean
there's various ways to do it some you
can do it for a single image for Google
Images you can do it which is what
batchman does you can also do it like on
a small piece of an image that's called
high pass filtering but the simplest
thing is and what almost everybody does
internet standard standard image that
pipeline or image processing image
recognition pipeline with commercial
nets for example is this
yeah the channels have very different
means and and so you know in a typical
natural image when you're in you know
outside and inside the the components
would be very different you have color
shift and the amplitude of blue is
relatively low for example if you are in
full Sun the amplitude of red is
basically non-existent if you are
underwater
so you know if if you want any kind of
signal you need to kind of normalize
this is basically like automatic gain
control the means are very different of
course because that depends on the
overall luminosity and you don't want a
system that where the recognition
depends too much on the global
illumination of your image so that's a
way of kind of getting rid of global
illumination if you want and sort of you
know kind of bad tuning of your exposure
or contrast or whatever it is but is
really good so numerical reasons for
doing this so in most precooked and
welcome back for why this is a good idea
okay
later in most pre-code code you will
also find things schedules to decrease
the running rate so the learning rate
the ADA system first of all most systems
don't use just plain stochastic gradient
they use things like atom which
automatically adapt the the step size or
other tricks they also use what's called
a momentum trick or necessary Fomento in
particular you know which atom
integrates and generally if you really
want good results you need to kind of
decrease your running way that as time
goes by and so there are kind of
standard ways of you know scheduling the
decrease of the learning rate that you
can use
occasionally not always you can use a
bit of l2 r1 regularization on the way
so what does that mean that means so l2
regularization means at every update you
multiply every way by one minus a small
constant multiplied by the learning rate
so basically and people call this way DK
says sessions call this l2
regularization this guy you have an
additional in in addition to your in
Europe in your last function in addition
to your cost you have a regularization
term that only depends on the weight the
cost depends on the sample as well right
and you have some sort of variable to
control these importance here so l2
regularization means our W equals the
square norm of W when you compute the
gradient of R with respect to a
particular component to W what you get
is to
- w hi and so in the update rule when
you do WI is replaced by WI - ADA
gradient of your overall loss with
respect to W what you get is WI - ADA
times the gradient of the cost with
respect to W - because it's a - gradient
- of WI oh you're right
which I can rewrite as so this is WI and
I can rewrite as WI times 1 minus 2
alpha minus C over D WI ok so what does
that mean you take every weight and at
every iteration you shrink it by a
constant that's slightly less than 1 and
so that's why it's called weight decay
in the absence of any gradient from
seeing the weights exponentially decay
to zero ok so what that does is that it
tries to tell the system you know
minimize my cost function but do it with
a weight vector that is as short as
possible
okay the other one is a one so l1
regularization
is basically a regularization term equal
to some of our I of absolute value of W
is for e which is yeah one norm so when
you do the the gradient a day you get WI
- yeah you see already WI and then
where's the gradient of this or - the
gradient of this that would be sine of
WI and of course you need e alpha in
front so this is a constant which is
positive which is positive if WI is
positive negative it is negative but
there's a minus sign in front so
basically here WI is being shrunk
towards zero by a constant equal to area
times alpha the state sessions converse
less soon
needs to absolute whatever okay I mean
it's some cute I quit name right this is
some sort of pun in it but and they
pronounce it let's sue for reason I
never understood and so that basically
shrinks the all the weights toward zero
by a constant and what that means is
that if a weight is not useful it's
gonna get eliminated to zero okay and
that is very interesting when you have
like a very large particularly a very
large uh like a network with a very
large number of inputs many of which are
not very useful this will basically
eliminate the inputs that are not very
useful because the weights that connect
to it will go to zero so when I did a
question okay so first of all you don't
want to use it at at the start because
there is a curious thing with neural
nets which is that the origin of weight
space is kind of a saddle point and so
if you if you crank up at one or l2
initially the weights just go to zero
and nothing works so so so it's in one
of the tricks actually I forgot a very
important one in this list which is that
the weights have to be initialized in
the neural net and they have to be
initialized properly these various
tricks that are built into PI torch to
initialize when trick is called the
climbing trick it's actually the glioma
to attract from 20 years earlier but and
the idea is it was reinvented multiple
times but the idea is you want the the
weights that they're going to a unit to
be to be random I mean you initialize
them randomly but you don't know them to
be too large or too small you want them
to be kind of roughly the right size so
that the output
is roughly the same variance as the
inputs okay so if the inputs to a unit
are independent the variance of the
output the variance of the weighted sum
will be equal to the sum of the
variances of the input multiplied by
weighted by the square of the weights
okay so if you want if you have n inputs
and you want the output to have the same
variance as the input and into weights
to be proportional to the inverse square
root of the number of inputs okay and
that's that's basically the trick so we
initialize the weights to values which
are drawn randomly with zero mean and
the variance is 1 over the square root
of the number of inputs to that unit
okay and that's you know hard you know
built into pie charts as well so
initialization is super important and it
can if you do it wrong your network is
not gonna cover yeah well I mean you
probably want to start with a alpha
equal zero and then maybe crank it up
and then it depends you know how much
you want to regularize how much is
necessary I mean a lot of people just
don't use any okay either everyone or l2
but they didn't drop out okay so the
road patch is another type of
regularization and and you can think of
it as a layer inside of a neural net
that you just insert in the neural net
where drop out does is that it randomly
it's a it's a box that has an input and
an output and it randomly sets n over
two of the outputs to zero and it's a
random draw at every new sample that you
draw that layer basically kills half of
its components okay this is crazy right
but in fact it kind of makes the other
variables more robust basically it
forces the system to not rely on
any single unit to produce an answer
it sort of distributes the information
across all the units because it knows
that you're in training you know half of
them can disappear so it tends to kind
of distribute the information better
it's a trick that you know Jeff Fenton
and his team came up with and turns out
to be you know quite efficient way of
regularizing neural nets a lot of people
use ok there's variations of it but and
we'll talk about more of those there are
in one of those papers efficient
backdrops that I wrote many years ago
and that you are invited to read ok last
thing for today even though we're late
this trick I mean it's this whole
framework of having a computer graph and
that propagating to it of course it
doesn't work just for stacked module it
works for any arrangement of module
including the ones that I dynamical that
depend on on on the inputs question
yeah so the question is why why do we
care about the fact that values are
scale equivariance if we're going to
normalize anyway the question is where
do you normalize to so if you have
sigmoids and you normalize you're
basically forcing the system if your
normal is it is a variance for example
is too small then the system is not
gonna be able to use the non-linearity
in the sigmoid hyperbole tangent let's
say if you make it too small is gonna
saturate so what's the right setup no
clear well you you don't care as long
it's the same variance all over the
network if you just let me variance all
over the network then you know what
you're gonna get issues some layers are
gonna learn faster than others some are
going to diverge when others are
converging so you want the variances to
be roughly the same all over the network
and you know that's what things like
betcha norm do for you we haven't talked
about batch alone yet but okay
that's it for today thank you see you
next week